Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're swimming.
今天我们聊游泳。
That's right.
没错。
A nice summertime lesson for everyone.
给大家带来一堂夏日主题的课。
A summertime lesson.
夏日主题的课。
So we're going to be talking about swimming and, well, it's a very popular sport, right?
所以我们要聊聊游泳，嗯，这是一项很受欢迎的运动，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So this is another lesson in our sports series.
这是我们运动系列中的另一节课。
In our sports series.
运动系列中的。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we preview some of the language we'll find in the dialogue.
那我们不如先预览一下对话中会出现的一些语言点。
Ready preview.
准备预览。
All right.
好的。
We have two words to look at here.
这里我们要看两个词。
The first word is sailing.
第一个词是sailing。
Sailing.
Sailing。
Well, this is the verb to sail, right?
嗯，这是动词to sail，对吧？
So sailing is traveling in a boat.
所以sailing就是在船上航行。
In a boat with no engine.
在没有引擎的船上。
Right.
对。
So you must use the wind to push you forward.
所以你必须利用风来推动你前进。
Exactly.
没错。
That's a sailboat.
那就是帆船。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So sailing.
所以sailing。
Now let's take a look at our other word.
现在我们来看看另一个词。
Anchor.
Anchor。
Another boat word here.
又一个跟船有关的词。
Anchor.
Anchor。
Now, it's spelled A-N-C-H-O-R.
它的拼写是A-N-C-H-O-R。
Right.
对。
But you don't pronounce the C-H as you normally would, right?
但你不像通常那样发C-H的音，对吧？
Another one of these really difficult to spell English words.
又一个很难拼写的英语单词。
Right.
对。
So you don't say anchor, you would say anchor.
所以你不说anchor，你会说anchor。
Anchor.
Anchor。
So the anchor is a verb and a noun.
所以anchor既是动词也是名词。
That's right.
没错。
So when anchor is used as a noun, it means the hook that you throw over the boat into
所以当anchor用作名词时，它指的是你从船上扔到水里的钩子，它能让船停在原地。
the water and it keeps you staying in the same place.
停在原地。
Okay.
好的。
But the verb to anchor.
但动词to anchor。
Yes.
是的。
What does it mean?
它是什么意思？
To do that.
就是做那个动作。
To do that, right?
做那个动作，对吧？
So to throw the anchor into the water, you would just say to anchor the boat.
所以把锚扔进水里，你只需要说to anchor the boat。
Exactly.
没错。
To keep it in the same place.
让船停在原地。
Okay.
好的。
Great words related to sailing.
跟航行相关的很棒词汇。
But now let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
但现在我们第一次听对话吧。
What's happening here, Erika?
这里发生了什么，Erika？
We've got two friends here who are sailing in their boat and they decide to take a swim.
有两个朋友在船上航行，他们决定下水游泳。
Let's see what happens.
我们看看会发生什么。
This is such a beautiful day.
今天天气真好。
Great day for sailing.
适合航行的好日子。
It sure is.
确实如此。
The water looks so nice.
水面看起来真美。
Anchor the boat for a little while.
把船锚停一会儿。
I'm going to take a dip.
我要下水游一会儿。
Why are you doggy paddling?
你为什么在狗刨？
I taught you how to swim.
我教过你怎么游泳。
Do your breast stroke.
用蛙泳。
I get too tired.
我游得太累了。
I'll just backstroke.
我就用仰泳。
It's easier.
更容易。
Try kicking your legs more.
试着多踢腿。
That's good.
不错。
Don't go out too far.
别游太远。
It's fine.
没事的。
Jump in.
跳下来。
Kathy, get back here.
Kathy，快回来。
I see a shark.
我看到一条鲨鱼。
Help me.
救命。
Help.
Bring the boat closer.
把船开近点。
The shark is coming straight towards me.
鲨鱼正朝我游过来。
It's right under you.
它就在你下面。
Kathy.
Kathy。
All right.
好了。
So a shark attack.
所以是鲨鱼袭击。
I know.
我知道。
This is my worst fear when swimming.
这是我游泳时最害怕的事。
Really in the ocean, right?
尤其是在海里，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Well, also in the lake, but...
嗯，湖里也是，不过……
No sharks in lakes.
湖里没有鲨鱼。
I know, but I'm still afraid of them.
我知道，但我还是怕它们。
All right, so don't worry about it.
好了，别担心。
I'm sure the girl is okay.
我确定那个女孩没事。
It's probably not a shark.
可能不是鲨鱼。
Maybe it was a dolphin.
也许是海豚。
Yeah, or maybe she's going to punch the shark in the face and she'll escape.
是啊，或者她可能会一拳打在鲨鱼脸上然后逃脱。
Okay.
好的。
Let's take a look at some of the words that we saw in Language Takeaway.
我们来看看“语言要点”里的一些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
We have three excellent swimming words for you.
我们为你准备了三个很棒的游泳词汇。
The first one is doggy paddling.
第一个是doggy paddling。
Doggy paddling.
Doggy paddling。
So doggy paddling.
所以doggy paddling。
It's not really a proper way of swimming, right?
这其实不是一种正规的游泳方式，对吧？
No, you don't see this in the Olympics.
不，你在奥运会上看不到这个。
So if you've ever seen a dog swim, that's why they call it doggy paddling.
如果你见过狗游泳，那就是为什么它叫doggy paddling。
Right.
对。
You're sort of moving your hands quickly in front of you.
你有点像在面前快速划动手。
And your legs are all over the place.
腿也乱动。
Yeah.
是的。
And you're basically not really swimming.
基本上你并不是真的在游泳。
You're just trying to stay afloat.
你只是试图浮在水面上。
You're trying not to drown.
你试图不溺水。
Trying not to sink.
试图不沉下去。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So doggy paddling.
所以doggy paddling。
Again, this can be a noun or a verb.
再说一次，这可以是名词或动词。
It's either doggy paddle, this swimming style, or doggy paddling, the verb.
要么是doggy paddle，这种游泳姿势，要么是doggy paddling，动词形式。
Okay.
好的。
Interesting.
有意思。
All right.
好了。
Let's take a look at our second swimming style.
我们来看看第二种游泳姿势。
Breaststroke.
Breaststroke。
The breaststroke.
蛙泳。
How is this one?
这个怎么样？
Well, it's sort of like swimming like a frog.
嗯，有点像青蛙游泳。
So you have your legs that are similar to like a frog, right?
所以你的腿像青蛙一样，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And what are your hands doing?
你的手在做什么？
Your hands are moving in front of you together, then out towards the side.
你的手在面前一起移动，然后向两侧展开。
Okay.
好的。
So you're kind of doing like circles.
所以你有点像在画圈。
Yeah.
是的。
Half circles.
半圆。
Okay.
好的。
Breaststroke.
Breaststroke。
Yeah.
是的。
But you get kind of tired when you swim like this, right?
但这样游会有点累，对吧？
Yeah, maybe.
嗯，可能吧。
Yeah.
是的。
Now, let's take a look at our third word.
现在，我们来看看第三个词。
Backstroke.
Backstroke。
So this one is pretty easy.
这个很简单。
Backstroke, you are?
Backstroke，你是？
Lying on your back.
仰面躺着。
In the water.
在水里。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
And you're kicking your feet as well.
你也在踢脚。
Yep.
是的。
But what are your hands doing?
但你的手在做什么？
They're going back behind you.
它们在你身后向后划。
See, I'm doing it now.
看，我现在就在做。
Can you see?
你能看到吗？
All right.
好了。
If you guys could be here in the studio, you would see Erika doing her backstroke.
如果你们能来演播室，就会看到Erika在做仰泳。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm pretty good at it.
我挺擅长的。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So let's listen to this dialogue again, and then we'll come back and look at some great
那我们再听一遍对话，然后回来看看一些很棒
phrases.
的短语。
This is such a beautiful day.
今天天气真好。
Great day for sailing.
适合航行的好日子。
It sure is.
确实如此。
The water looks so nice.
水面看起来真美。
Anchor the boat for a little while.
把船锚停一会儿。
I'm going to take a dip.
我要下水游一会儿。
Why are you doggy paddling?
你为什么在狗刨？
I taught you how to swim.
我教过你怎么游泳。
Do your breaststroke.
用蛙泳。
I get too tired.
我游得太累了。
I'll just backstroke.
我就用仰泳。
It's easier.
更容易。
Try kicking your legs more.
试着多踢腿。
That's good.
不错。
Don't go out too far.
别游太远。
It's fine.
没事的。
Jump in.
跳下来。
Kathy, get back here.
Kathy，快回来。
I see a shark.
我看到一条鲨鱼。
Help me!
救命！
Help!
Bring the boat closer.
把船开近点。
The shark is coming straight towards me.
鲨鱼正朝我游过来。
It's right under you.
它就在你下面。
Kathy!
凯西！
Okay, so we have some really good phrases related to swimming and water.
好，我们有一些和游泳、水相关的很棒短语。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay, let's take a look at these in Fluency Builder.
好，我们来看看这些在流利度练习中的内容。
Fluency Builder.
流利度练习。
All right, the first one.
好的，第一个。
I love this phrase.
我喜欢这个短语。
Take a dip.
泡一下。
So if I say, I'm going to take a dip.
所以如果我说，我要去泡一下。
You're going to have a quick swim.
就是快速游个泳。
A quick swim.
快速游个泳。
Yep.
对。
So you can take a dip in the pool.
所以你可以在泳池里泡一下。
Yep.
对。
In the lake.
在湖里。
In the ocean.
在海里。
Even in your bathtub, right?
甚至在你的浴缸里，对吧？
No.
不。
No?
不？
No, it's just for swimming.
不，这只是用于游泳。
Unless your bathtub is really, really, really big.
除非你的浴缸非常大、非常大、非常大。
All right, so not for the bathtub, but for swimming.
好吧，所以不是用于浴缸，而是用于游泳。
Yep.
对。
Okay.
好。
Now, let's take a look at our second phrase.
现在，我们来看看第二个短语。
For a little while.
一会儿。
This is really common.
这个很常见。
I use this a lot.
我经常用这个。
Yeah, me too.
是啊，我也是。
I probably use it 500 times a day.
我可能一天用五百次。
Okay, so let's listen to some examples with for a little while, and then we'll come back
好，我们来听一些用“一会儿”的例子，然后回来
and explain it.
解释它。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm tired.
我累了。
I'm just going to sit down for a little while.
我就坐一会儿。
Example two.
例子二。
It will only hurt for a little while.
只会疼一会儿。
Example three.
例子三。
Do you want to play tennis for a little while?
你想打一会儿网球吗？
So it means for a short time.
所以它的意思是短时间。
For a short time.
短时间。
And you can change it, right?
而且你可以改变它，对吧？
You can say, oh, I'm going to play for a little while.
你可以说，哦，我要玩一会儿。
Yeah, or I'm going to sleep for a little while.
是啊，或者我要睡一会儿。
For a short time.
短时间。
Yep.
对。
All right, so if learners use this phrase, I find it sounds really, really great because
好，如果学习者用这个短语，我觉得听起来会非常非常好，因为
it's not something that students normally use.
这不是学生通常用的东西。
Yeah, I guess a student wouldn't really use this phrase normally.
是啊，我猜学生通常不会用这个短语。
Yeah, so guys, use it because you'll sound awesome.
对，所以各位，用它吧，因为你会听起来很棒。
Yeah, you'll sound really, really fluent.
是啊，你会听起来非常非常流利。
Okay, and let's take a look at our last phrase.
好，我们来看看最后一个短语。
Straight towards.
径直朝。
Straight towards me.
径直朝我。
Straight towards.
径直朝。
Okay, so straight means directly.
好，所以“straight”意思是直接地。
Right, in a line.
对，成一条直线。
In a line, not going anywhere else, but directly.
成一条直线，不拐弯，直接地。
Not moving side to side.
不左右移动。
And towards is in that direction.
而“towards”是朝那个方向。
So the shark was coming straight towards me, it's coming directly at me.
所以鲨鱼径直朝我游过来，它直接冲我来。
Moving in a line and not moving side to side.
成一条直线移动，不左右移动。
Okay, so can you give me another example of how you would use straight towards?
好，你能给我另一个怎么用“straight towards”的例子吗？
Watch out!
小心！
The shark is coming straight towards you.
鲨鱼正径直朝你游过来。
Okay, directly towards you.
好，直接朝你。
Yeah, or maybe when I get home from work, I go straight towards the fridge.
是啊，或者也许我下班回家时，我径直朝冰箱走去。
Really?
真的吗？
Yes.
是的。
I believe this.
我相信这个。
All right, so straight towards, directly.
好，所以“straight towards”就是直接地。
Okay, so we've looked at a lot of great words, really good phrases.
好，我们看了很多好词，非常好的短语。
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time and then we'll come back and Erica is going
让我们最后听一遍这段对话，然后回来，Erica会
to tell us a really great story about boat.
给我们讲一个关于船的很棒的故事。
This is such a beautiful day.
今天天气真好。
Great day for sailing.
适合航行的好日子。
It sure is.
确实是啊。
The water looks so nice.
水看起来真不错。
Anchor the boat for a little while.
把船锚定一会儿。
I'm going to take a dip.
我要去泡一下。
Why are you doggy paddling?
你为什么在狗刨？
I taught you how to swim.
我教过你怎么游泳。
Do your breaststroke.
做你的蛙泳。
I get too tired.
我太累了。
I'll just backstroke.
我就仰泳吧。
It's easier.
更容易些。
Try kicking your legs more.
试着多踢腿。
That's good.
不错。
Don't go out too far.
别游太远。
It's fine.
没事。
Jump in.
跳进来。
Cathy, get back here.
凯西，回来。
I see a shark.
我看到一条鲨鱼。
Help me!
救命！
Help!
Bring the boat closer.
把船开近点。
The shark is coming straight towards me.
鲨鱼正径直朝我游过来。
It's right under you.
它就在你下面。
Cathy!
凯西！
All right, well, Marco, I was telling you that I used to spend every summer on the lake
好，嗯，Marco，我正告诉你我以前每个夏天都在湖上度过，
and my family had a really small house on a small island and my cousins had another
我家在一个小岛上有一个很小的房子，我表亲家在另一个小岛上也有一个
small house on another small island.
小房子。
So our families are really close and we used to go to one house for dinner one night and
所以我们家很亲近，我们以前一晚去一家吃晚饭，
the other house to dinner the next night.
第二晚去另一家吃晚饭。
So everyone was over at my cousin's house except for my grandfather.
所以除了我爷爷，大家都在我表亲家。
And so he was thinking, okay, it's late, maybe I better go pick up my wife and see what's
然后他想，好吧，天晚了，也许我该去接我妻子看看
going on.
怎么回事。
So he goes into the boat.
所以他上了船。
It's dark.
天黑了。
Okay.
好。
There's no light on the boat.
船上没有灯。
He's driving straight towards the island when suddenly my cousin in his boat drives directly
他正径直朝岛开去，突然我表亲开着他的船直接
into my grandfather.
撞上了我爷爷。
So they crashed.
所以他们撞了。
They crashed.
他们撞了。
Two boats crashed in the lake.
两艘船在湖里撞了。
And then my grandfather's boat flipped over.
然后我爷爷的船翻了。
It turned upside down.
它底朝天了。
And he fell in the water.
他掉进了水里。
But he was okay, right?
但他没事，对吧？
Yeah, he was okay.
是啊，他没事。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
He was really angry about this.
他对这件事非常生气。
And the boat?
那船呢？
The boat stayed in the water and the engine fell down to the bottom.
船留在了水里，发动机掉到了湖底。
So we had to go the next morning to get the boat.
所以我们第二天早上得去捞船。
And we actually had to hire some scuba divers to go to the bottom of the lake to get the
我们实际上雇了一些潜水员去湖底捞
engine.
发动机。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah.
是啊。
I imagine your grandpa was pretty angry.
我猜你爷爷当时很生气。
Yeah.
是啊。
He tells the story.
他讲这个故事。
Every year.
每年都讲。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
I've got a million of these crazy lake stories because my family.
我有一大堆这种疯狂的湖上故事，因为我家……
It always happens.
这种事总是发生。
Yeah.
是啊。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
Well, do you have any crazy stories or any stories related to boats or to swimming?
嗯，你们有没有什么疯狂的故事，或者和船或游泳有关的故事？
Or to shark attacks?
或者和鲨鱼袭击有关？
Or shark attacks?
或者鲨鱼袭击？
Yeah.
是啊。
So come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Leave your stories.
留下你们的故事。
Share with us.
和我们分享。
And also, if you have any doubts or questions, Erika and I are always there to answer.
还有，如果你们有任何疑问或问题，Erika和我总是在那里回答。
Well, we're out of time for this lesson.
好了，这节课的时间到了。
But until next time, goodbye.
但下次再见，拜拜。